<resources>
    <string name="app_name">MenudTry2</string>
    <string name="title_activity_menu">MenuActivity</string>
    <string name="action_settings">Settings</string>
    <string name="section_format">Hello World from section: %1$d</string>
    <string name="health_article">
        Diet, Exercise and Bone Health



   As a fitness pro, you cant fix the genetic and environmental contributors to bone loss, but you can encourage physical activity and proper nutrition, both of which improve bone health. More than 70% of Americans dont get the recommended amount of physical activity (Laskowski 2012), and 50% are considered deficient in vitamin D (Karaguzel and Holick 2010). One systematic review rated calcium, vitamin D, dairy and physical activity/exercise as the most important modifiable lifestyle factors that can influence the development of peak bone mass (NOF 2016).

Physical Activity

According to the Surgeon General, physical activity is one of the most important controllable lifestyle changes to help prevent (or reduce the risk of) a number of chronic diseases (OSG 2004), and although it is a leading health indicator, more than 80% of adults do not meet the guidelines for both aerobic and muscle-strengthening activities (ODPHP 2018).

McMillan et al. (2017) state that physical inactivity, or sedentary behavior, has been described as the major public health problem of our time. Physical activity is known to influence both bone and muscle metabolism; therefore, inactivityor a decline in activitycan affect bone through those two pathways (Tagliaferri et al. 2015). Osteogenesis occurs in response to mechanical loading. Inactivity, with its lack of loading, prevents bones from receiving the signal to adapt, which causes bone loss. Its a basic use-it-or-lose-it scenario.

While all exercises affect muscle and bone, recent research indicates that some activities help bones more than others. In program development, it is important to consider that the skeletal sites closest to the engaged muscle will have the biggest BMD increases (McMillan et al. 2017). For example, in sprinters and shot putters, BMD is highest in the legs and dominant arm, respectively. This is helpful to know when working with clients who have compromised BMD in certain sites.

Muscles are the key factor in exerting mechanical force on the skeleton, so increasing muscle strength is importantespecially in the bones most likely to fracture (hips, wrists, vertebrae, etc.). See the article Exercises for Clients with Osteoporosis for bone-building exercises.

Nutrition

Proper diet pulls double duty: developing skeletal strength and maintaining bones role as a mineral storehouse. Minerals such as calcium and phosphorus, which the body must have in order to perform every day, are stored in bone. If the body cant get these minerals from our diet, it takes them from our bones, reducing bone mass and strength (OSG 2004).

After age 30, calcium deficiencies can lead to a gradual bone loss as high as 0.5% per year (Karaguzel and Holick 2010). Calcium is a crucial part of young peoples diets, as half of the calcium in the adult skeleton is deposited during the ages of 1317 (Karaguzel and Holick 2010).

Consuming calcium on its own, however, is not enough. Proper absorption of calcium depends on sufficient vitamin D intake, and some research has even suggested that calcium supplements without vitamin D supplementation may increase the risk of myocardial infarction (Rizzoli 2014). Interestingly, this increased risk is not evident when calcium is consumed from food, which is the intake method that is most highly recommended. Calcium can be obtained from a variety of food sources and, even for people with dietary restrictions such as dairy intolerance, there are many food sources available.

Dairy products, however, are the most efficient way to get enough calcium. One study evaluated the importance of dairy in calcium delivery and found that although calcium supplements can influence bone remodeling, dairy products have an additional benefit for bone growth. Dairy products provide more calcium, protein, magnesium, potassium, zinc and phosphorus per calorie than any other food (Rizzoli 2014). It would take 48 servings of whole grains or 24 servings of green vegetables to provide as much calcium as there is in a 200-millileter (6.76-ounce) glass of milk.

You may also have seen milk advertised as the perfect postworkout drink. Research into the effectiveness of fat-free milk versus an isoenergetic carbohydrate drink after resistance training found that milk promoted fat loss, lean-mass gains and BMD (Rizzoli 2014). Because calcium and vitamin D go hand in hand, many milks and yogurts are now fortified with vitamin D. Note that exposure to sunlight is still the most effective way to get enough vitamin D (Karaguzel and Holick 2010).

Although vitamin D is the main factor in calcium absorption, research suggests that absorption increases with higher dietary protein consumption in postmenopausal women (Tagliaferri et al. 2015) and that higher protein intake correlates to a lower rate of age-related bone loss (IOF 2017).
    </string>
    <string name="title_activity_article">Article</string>
    <string name="health_article2">WEEKEND RECIPE:An Asparagus Salad That Will Wow Dinner Guests   I love this beautiful and simple salad that is filled with goodness. It takes just a few minutes to prepare and you can serve it for lunch or dinner or even a nourishing breakfast. I like to enjoy my salad topped with thinly sliced feta or a generous grating of pecorino. The slightly salty feta marries perfectly with the subtle earthy flavors of asparagus and a drizzle of extra virgin olive oil scented with lemon and fresh herbs.  For added protein, top the asparagus with medium to hard-boiled eggs that youve shelled and cut in half. Its also great with steamed or pan-roasted fish, smoked salmon or thinly sliced poached chicken. For a plant-based protein option, I love topping the asparagus with shelled broad beans or green peas that have been lightly braised in a little water and sea salt. WHATS GREAT ABOUT IT:  Asparagus is a wonderful source of folate and vitamins A, C and K. Asparagus is also a good source of inulin, a dietary fiber that can help control hunger and manage weight. Inulin also works as a prebiotic and can help stimulate the growth of healthy bacteria in the digestive system. This delicious and simple recipe is from my Healthy Chef Recipe App.  INGREDIENTS  Serves 4  60ml (2 fl oz / 1/4 cup) extra virgin olive oil 3 tablespoons lemon juice 2 tablespoons fresh chopped parsley 2 tablespoons fresh chopped chives Sea salt and cracked pepper to taste 600g (21 oz) asparagus, ends trimmed and lightly peeled 200g (7 oz) feta, sliced DIRECTIONS  Combine olive oil, lemon, parsley and chives into a small mixing bowl Add a pinch of salt and pepper and taste for seasoning Whisk until combined then set the dressing aside Blanch the asparagus for 1 minute in boiling water then remove with a slotted spoon. You can also steam them by putting the asparagus into a large pan with a generous splash of water, then covering the pan for 2 to 3 minutes until just tender Arrange asparagus onto a serving plate Top with fine slices of feta and drizzle over the gorgeous herb and lemon dressing</string>
    <string name="health_article3">Weekend Recipe: Healthy Chocolate Chip Cookies    This healthy chocolate chip cookie recipe is super easy to make. My secret is to use good-quality dark eating chocolate. The 70  80% cocoa type such as Lindt, which is not too sweet. Using quality ingredients will create the most delicious cookie, and will be perfect with your next pot of tea or to dunk into a glass of icy cold almond milk.  You dont need any special equipment to make this recipe, just a bowl for mixing the ingredients with your hands. I always double or triple the recipe because they dont last long in my home. WHATS GREAT ABOUT THEM  The ground almonds in this recipe make a wonderful replacement for the traditional white refined flours that youll find in most store bought cookies. Almonds are a good source of protein and are packed with vitamin E.  INGREDIENTS  300 g (3 cups / 10 1/2 oz) almond meal / ground almonds 6 tablespoons extra virgin olive oil or cold pressed macadamia nut oil 4 tablespoons raw honey 1 teaspoon vanilla bean extract 100g (3 1/2 oz) good quality dark eating chocolate (I used 1 block of 70% Lindt chocolate and a little water for mixing) DIRECTIONS  Preheat your oven to 140 C (280 F) Combine almond meal, oil, honey and vanilla bean into a mixing bowl Mix with your hands and form into a soft dough Add a splash of water 1  2 teaspoons to help form dough, otherwise it will start to crumble Chop chocolate with a knife into small chips Add chocolate into the cookie dough mix and combine with your hands so that its distributed evenly Using a small ice cream scoop or spoon, form dough into 20 cookies and place evenly onto a prepared baking tray Press the top of the cookie gently to flatten slightly. I also like to garnish with a little flaked almond before baking for decoration, but this is optional Bake in a low oven for 30 minutes until golden Cool completely before devouring NOTES + INSPIRATION: You can add 2 tablespoons of cacao to the mixture for a yummy double chocolate chip cookie. You can also add the zest of an orange to give it a glorious jaffa flavor.  Teresa Cutter, founder of The Healthy Chef, is an author, nutritionist and classically trained chef. You can find more of Cutters tips and recipes on her website, app, eBooks and Instagram.  My main goal at The Healthy Chef is to get people cooking and eating healthier. Eat natural foods, focus on fresh fruits and vegetables and just keep it simple.  Teresa Cutter</string>
</resources>
